<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="treeland_manager_v1">
    <copyright>
        Copyright © 2023 Uniontech

        Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
        copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
        to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
        the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
        and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
        Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

        The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
        paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
        Software.

        THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
        IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
        FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
        THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
        LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
        FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
        DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
    </copyright>
    <interface name="treeland_socket_manager_v1" version="1">
        <description summary="client socket manager">
        This interface allows a client to register a new Wayland socket for a new user logind.

        Warning! The protocol described in this file is currently in the testing
        phase. Backward compatible changes may be added together with the
        corresponding interface version bump. Backward incompatible changes can
        only be done by creating a new major version of the extension.
        </description>
        <request name="create">
            <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="treeland_socket_context_v1"/>
        </request>
    </interface>
    <interface name="treeland_socket_context_v1" version="1">
        <description summary="client socket context">
        This interface allows a client to register a new Wayland socket for a new user logind.

        Warning! The protocol described in this file is currently in the testing
        phase. Backward compatible changes may be added together with the
        corresponding interface version bump. Backward incompatible changes can
        only be done by creating a new major version of the extension.
        </description>
        <enum name="error">
            <entry name="already_set" value="1"
                summary="user socket has already been committed"/>
            <entry name="invalid_user" value="2"
                summary="username is invalid" />
            <entry name="invalid_fd" value="3"
                summary="user wayland socket is invalid" />
        </enum>
        <request name="set_username">
            <arg name="username" type="string" summary="create a user wayland socket"/>
        </request>
        <request name="set_fd">
            <arg name="fd" type="fd" summary="FD when user wayland display"/>
        </request>
        <request name="commit">
            <description summary="register the user wayland socket">
                Atomically register the new client and attach the wayland socket context
                metadata.

                It's a protocol error to send any request other than "destroy" after
                this request. In this case, the already_used error is sent.
            </description>
        </request>
        <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
            <description summary="destroy the context object">
                Destroy the context object.
            </description>
        </request>
    </interface>
</protocol>
